Finding Aid for the Japanese American Research Project Collection about Japanese in the U.S. (Yuji Ichioka papers) LSC.2010.00
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Organizational Materials
  - Pre-War Japanese Religious Organizations
    - Publications By or regarding Pre-War Religious Organizations
      - Books, booklets, and pamphlets published by or regarding religious organizations. (Box 295)
        - Seich no Ie Hombu [characters]. Beikoku ni okeru Kami no Sokuseki [characters] [God's imprints in America]. Tokyo: Kmy Shis Fuky Kai., 1939; (1 item, 211 pp.) (Box 295)
          The Seich no Ie was first introduced in America in 1938.
        - Shatoru Nihonjin Mesojisuto Kykai [characters] [Seattle Japanese Methodist Church]. Sritsu Yonj-go-nen Kineng [characters] [Forty-fifth anniversary, 1904-1949]. Seattle., (1 item, 8pp., and 7 pp.) (Box 295)
        - Sk Bukky Kai [characters]. Sk Bukky Kai Kaiky Sanj-nen Kinen Shi [characters] [A commemorative publication to mark the 30th anniversary of the San Francisco Buddhist Church]. San Francisco: Sk Bukky Kai., 1930; (1 item, 265 pp.) (Box 295)
          The Sk Bukky Kai was established in 1899. This book includes a chronological list of ministers, the organization's rules and regulations, and 1929 Fiscal Report.
        - TGA Yoichi [characters], ed. Hokka Kirisuto Kykai Benran [characters] [Handbook of the Japanese Christian Churches in Northern California]. San Francisco: Hokka Kirisuto Kykai Dmei [characters]., 1936; (1 item, 243 pp.) (Box 295)
          "A useful reference book."
        - TSUNODA Rysaku [characters]. The Essence of Japanese Buddhism. Honolulu: The Advertiser Press., 1914; (1 item, 84 pp.) (Box 295)
        - UTSUKI Nissh. The Shin Sect: A School of Mahayana Buddhism. Kyoto: Hompa Hongwanji., 1937; (1 item, 49 pp.) (Box 295)
        - YUKI Shjir [characters]. Rafu Nihonjin Mii Kykai Yonj-nen Shi [characters] [A 40-year history of the Los Angeles Methodist Episcopal Church]. Los Angeles: Rafu Nihonjin Mii Kykai., 1937; (1 item, 188 pp.) (Box 295)
          The Los Angeles Methodist Episcopal Church was founded in 1896 as the first Japanese Christian Church in the Los Angeles area.
  - Pre-War Japanese Socio-Cultural Organizations
    - Socio-Cultural Organizations in California, 2.5 linear ft.
      - Kash Nihonjin Jikei Kai [characters] [Japanese Benevolent Society]. San Francisco. (Box 264)
        It was established in 1901.
        - Dai-nij-yon-nendo hkoku [characters] [Report: Fiscal year 1924-1925]., August 1924-June 1925; (1 item) (Box 264)
      - Korsa Bosan Kai [characters] [Colusa Memorial Society], Colusa, California. (Box 264)
        - Kiroku [characters] [Records]., January 1919-May 1949; (1 item) (Box 264)
      - Nihonjin Yrin [characters] [Japanese Old People's Home], Los Angeles. (Box 264)
        It was built in Boyle Heights, Los Angeles, and its construction was completed in 1939.
        - Correspondence., December 1935-May 1940; (22 items) (Box 264)
        - Hkoku-sho [characters] [Reports]., 1938-1939; (2 items) (Box 264)
        - Kifusha hmei [characters] [Donors' roster]., May 1931-April 1941; (1 book and 7 items) (Box 264)
        - Records on the Japanese government subsidies., December 1938-February 1940; (13 items) (Box 264)
        - Miscellaneous papers and records., 1936-1941; (5 items) (Box 264)
      - Rafu Kinshu Kai [characters] [Prohibition Society of Los Angeles], Los Angeles. (Box 264)
        It was organized by the Japanese Christian Church Federation of Southern California (see Box 280) in February 1908.
        - Kiroku [characters] [Records]., February 12, 1908-February 18, 1910; (1 item) (Box 264)
      - Rosuanzerusu-gun Nihonjin Jind Kai [characters] [Japanese Humane Society of Los Angeles], Los Angeles. (Box 264)
        It was founded in January 1912.
        - Kifusha hmei [characters] [Donors' list]., March 1912-June 1923; (1 item) (Box 264)
      - Trakku Fujin Kai [characters] [Women's Society of Turlock], Turlock, California. (Box 268)
        - Gijiroku [characters] [Minutes of meetings]., January 1940-April 1941; (2 binders) (Box 268)
        - Kaikeibo [characters] [Account books]., February 1940-January 1942; (2 binders) (Box 268)
        - Kaikei, zatsu [characters] [Account books, miscellaneous items]., February 1930-December 1940; (117 pieces) (Box 268)
        - Tban meibo [characters] [Duty roster]., 1940; (1 item) (Box 268)
      - Trakku Shak Kurabu [characters] [Turlock Social Club], Turlock. (Box 265-267)
        It began as the Turlock Japanese Community Hall of the Sutanisurausu Nihonjin Kai [Japanese Association of Stanislaus] (see Box 241). The social and community events held at the Hall and various functions it performed were later separated from the jurisdiction of the Japanese Association, and a new organization called the Trakku Shak Kurabu was formed. After the Japanese Association of Stanislaus was officially dissolved in 1928, the Club assumed some of its functions (e.g., issuance of various certificates required by the Japanese government laws and regulations).
        - Buhi-kankei kiroku [characters] [Records on membership fees and related matters]., 1926-1939; (40 items) (Box 265)
        - Correspondence., January 4, 1925-August 15, 1941; (13 letters and 2 cablegrams) (Box 267)
        - Financial records., 1919-1931; (6 folders) (Box 267)
        - Kiroku [characters] [Records]., December 1922-December 1924; (1 book) (Box 266)
        - Kiroku oyobi kaikeibo [characters] [Records of various activities and expenditures]., December 1925-January 1939 (Box 267)
        - Sgo kysai-kai saisoku oyobi kaikeibo [characters] [Bylaws of the Mutual Aid Society, and ledger]., 1939-1941 (Box 266)
    - Socio-Cultural Organization in Colorado, 0.5 linerar ft.
      - Nankaku Shykai [characters] [Southern Colorado Character Building Society], Swink, Colorado. (Box 269)
        It was organized in 1911 with a view toward improving the moral and intellectual character of the Japanese residing in Southern Colorado.
        - Nankaku Shykai kiroku [characters] [Records of the Southern Colorado Character Building Society]., February 8, 1925-August 27, 1939; (1 book) (Box 269)
    - Socio-Cultural Organization in Hawaii, 0.5 linear ft.
      - Maui Kyiku Kai [characters] [Maui Educational Society], Wailuku. (Box 271)
        - Kaiin meibo [characters] [Membership roster]., July 1931; (1 item) (Box 271)
    - Socio-Cultural Organizations in Idaho
      - Pokatero Nihonjin Seinen Kai [characters] [Japanese Youth Association of Pocatello], Pocatello, Idaho. (Box 269)
        It was established in February 1915 as a fraternal organization, and was renamed as the Pokatero Aiykai [characters] [Japanese I.U. Association of Pocatello] later.
        - Kaikeibo [characters] [Account book]., December 1915-August 1917; (1 book) (Box 269)
        - Kiroku [characters] [Records], vol.1-2., February 7, 1915-September 2, 1917; January 2, 1916-September 15, 1919; (2 books) (Box 269)
    - Socio-Cultural Organization in Washington, 1.0 linear ft.
      - Tokushima Kenjin Kai [characters] [Tokushima Prefectural Association], Seattle. (Box 270-271)
        - AKAHORI Masaru [characters], Zaibei Tokushima Kenjin Shi genk [characters] [A draft history of the Japanese from Tokushima Prefecture in America]., 1941; (Manuscripts, 8 items) (Box 271)
        - Kaikeibo [characters] [Account book]., June 1914-January 1921; (1 item) (Box 270)
        - Kiroku [characters] [Records]., 1902-1924; (5 items) (Box 270)
        - Kdoku-kai kiroku [characters] [Book Club records]., March 1910-January 1912; (1 item) (Box 270)
        - Kyiku-kai meibo [characters] [Membership roster: Education Society]., 1931; (1 item) (Box 271)
    - Publications By or regarding Pre-War Japanese Socio-Cultural Organizations, 0.5 linear ft.
      - [Japan America Society of Los Angeles]. Japan America Society of Los Angeles, 1909-1934. Los Angeles. A silver anniversary booklet., (1 item) (Box 271)
      - Nanka Shnien [characters]. Nanka Shnien Shshi [characters] [The Japanese Children's Home of Southern California]. Los Angeles: Nanka Shnien., 1939; (1 item, 29pp. and 6 pp.) (Box 271)
      - Nichi-Boku Kykai [characters]. Nichi-Boku Kykai Kaih [characters] [Japan-Mexico Society Bulletin], no.1-2. Tokyo., April 30, 1916; March 30, 1927; (2 items) (Box 271)
      - Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai [characters]. Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai Yran [characters] [Japan-America-Hawaii Society]. Tokyo: Nihon Bei-Fu Kykai. A booklet., 1937; (46pp., 1 item) (Box 271)
      - Tokushima Kenjin Kai [characters]. Tokushima Kenjin Kai Kaih [characters] [Bulletin of the Tokushima Prefectural Association]. Seattle: Tokushima Kenjin Kai., 1915; (126pp., 1 item) (Box 271)
      - Social Solidarity Among the Japanese in Seattle. Bulletin University of Washington., (129pp., 1 item.) (Box 796, Folder 1)
  - Publications By or regarding Pre-War Economic Organizations, 1.0 linear ft.
    - Japanese American Trade Year Book 1918, 1919-20 (Two Volumes) (Box 867)
      Two volumes of Japanese American Trade Year Book published by Japanese Chamber of Commerce.
    - Jitsugy Gepp [characters] [The Japanese Industrial Report]., 1916; (3 items) (Box 279)
      It was published by the Rafu Nihonjin Jitsugy Kumiai [Japanese Businessmen's Association of Los Angeles] (see Box 272).
      no.1 (November 5, 1916)
      no.2 (December 5, 1916)
      no.3 (January 5, 1916)
    - Kash Kaki Ichiba Gepp [characters] [California Flower Market Monthly], no.5., August 5, 1929; (1 issue) (Box 279)
      It was published by the Kash Kaki Ichiba [California Flower Market] in San Francisco.
    - Kash Kaki Ichiba Kabushiki Kaisha [characters] [California Flower Market, Inc.]. Kash Nihonji Kaengy Hatten Shi [characters] [History of Japanese Floriculture in California]. San Francisco: Kash Kaki Ichiba Kabushiki Kaisha., 1929; (321pp., 1 volume) (Box 279)
    - Kash Nihonjin Ch Nkai [characters]. Rn Konshinkai Kinen [characters] [Conference of experienced farmers]. San Francisco: Kash Nihonjin Ch Nkai, 1909., (166p., 1 item) (Box 279)
      The proceedings of a conference of Japanese farmers held in Stockton, California in January 1909.
    - Nanka Shh [characters] [Nanka Merchant's Bulletin]., September 20, 1939; January 20, February 20; June 30 1940; August, September 30, 1941; (6 issues) (Box 279)
      It was published by the Nanka Shgy Kumiai [characters] [Association of Japanese Retail Grocers and Merchants of Southern California], Los Angeles.
      vol.14, no.9 (September 20, 1939)
      vol.15, no.1 (January 20, 1940)
      vol.15, no.2 (February 20, 1940)
      vol.15, no.6 (June 30, 1940)
      vol.16, no.8 (August 1941)
      vol.16, no.9 (September 30, 1941)
    - Shgy Kaigisho Gepp [characters] [Chamber of Commerce Monthly Report], no.1-45, 58., February 5, 1917-December 25, 1922; May 10, 1924; (47 issues) (Box 279)
      It was published by the Nanka Nihonjin Shgy Kaigisho [Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California] (see Box 272). The title was changed to the Nanka Nihonjin Shgy Kaigisho Gepp [characters] [Monthly Report of the Japanese Chamber of Commerce of Southern California] from No. 19.
    - Sk Bijutsu Zakkash Dmei Kai [characters] [Japanese Art Goods Merchants' Association of San Francisco]. Sk Bijutsu Zakkash Dmei Kai Yran [characters] [Japanese Art Goods Merchants' Association]. San Francisco: Sk Bijutsu Zakkash Dmei Kai., 1936; (71 pp.) (Box 279)
    - The History of Southern California Florist's Association (1933) (Box 867)
      Japanese language book published by Southern California Florist's Association.
    - Northern California Japanese Farmers Association: 30 Years Anniversary, 1960 (Box 869)
      A Japanese language book published in 1960 by Dai Nihon Noh Kai (Japanese Farmers Association) to cerebrate its 30 years anniversary of the founding in Northern California. The content includes the timeline and historical descriptions of the association originally started in Japan in 1881.
- Materials regarding Japanese language schools
  - Japanese Language School Records and Documents, 1.0 linear ft.
    - Trakku Nihongo Gakuen [characters] [Turlock Japanese Language School]. Turlock, California. (Box 319)
      Trakku Nihongo Gakuen [characters] [Turlock Japanese Language School]. Turlock, California.
      - Kaikeibo [characters] [Account book]., January 1930-January 1938; (1 item) (Box 319)
      - Minutes of P.T.A. meetings., 1931; (1 item) (Box 319)
      - Miscellaneous financial records., April 1934-October 1941 (Box 319)
      - Kaikeibo [characters] [Account book]., January 1930-January 1938; (1 item) (Box 319)
    - Ktezu Nihongo Gakuen [characters] [Cortez Japanese Language School]. Cortez, California. (Box 320)
      Ktezu Nihongo Gakuen [characters] [Cortez Japanese Language School]. Cortez, California. Kaikeibo [characters]
      - [Account book]., 1939-1941; (1 item) (Box 320)
    - Wairuku Gakuen [characters] [Wailuku Japanese Language School], Wailuku, Hawaii. (Box 320)
      Wairuku Gakuen [characters] [Wailuku Japanese Language School], Wailuku, Hawaii.
      - Shinchiku kifu hmei taibo [characters] [List of donors for the construction of a new school building]., 1927; 3 books) (Box 320)
  - Japanese Language School Textbooks, 5.5 linear ft.
    - Textbooks Compiled and Published in the United States, 1.0 linear ft.
      - Beikoku Nihongo Kenky kai [characters]. Atarashii Nihongo [characters] [New Japanese Language], 2nd year. 4th printing. Los Angeles: Beikoku Nihongo Kenky kai., 1962; (46pp. 2 volumes) (Box 321)
      - Hawai Chgakk [characters] [Hawaii Middle School]. New Standard Translation Text. Honolulu: Hawai Chgakk., 1928; 1931; (2 books) (Box 321)
        Book 1, revised edition, 1931, 48pp.
        Book 4, 1928, 48pp.
      - Hawai Kyiku Kai [characters] [Hawaii Educational Society]. Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [Japanese Language Reader]. Honolulu: Hawai Kyiku Kai., 1929; (2 books) (Box 321)
        Book 5, 217pp.; and Book 6, 190pp.
      - Hawai Kyiku Kai. Nihongo Tokuhon: Chtkay, Maki-ni [characters] [Japanese Language Reader: Intermediate, Series 2]. Honolulu: Hawai Kyiku Kai., 1930; (238 pp.) (Box 321)
      - Hawai Kyiku Kai. Nihongo Tokuhon: Ktkay [characters] [Japanese Language Reader: Advanced series]. Honolulu: Fushimi-no-Miya Kinen Shgakkai., n.d.; (2 books) (Box 321)
        Volume 1, 320pp.; and Volume 2, 330pp.
      - Hawai Kyiku Kai. Shshin-sho [characters] [Shshin Textbook]. Honolulu: Hawai Kyiku Kai., 1932; (172 pp.) (Box 321)
      - Hompa Honganji Gakumu-bu [characters]. Cht Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [Japanese Language Reader: Intermediate]. Volume 2. Honolulu: Hompa Honganji Gakumu-bu (revised edition)., 1925 and 1929; (2 books: 120 pp. and 145 pp.) (Box 321)
      - Hompa Honganji Gakumu-bu. Hanashikata to Shokanbun [characters] [How to talk, and how to write letters]. Honolulu: Hompa Hongwanji Gakumu-bu., 1927; (191 pp.) (Box 321)
        Revised edition, 2nd printing.
      - [Hompa] Honganji Gakumu-bu. Nihongo Fukutokuhon [characters] [Japanese Language supplementary reader]. Volumes 1-5. Honolulu: Hongwanji Gakumu-bu., 1928; (5 volumes) (Box 321)
      - KAWAMURA Ysen (Masahei) [characters], ed. Amerika Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [The American Japanese Language Reader]. San Francisco: Beikoku Nikkei Jid Kyiku Kenky Kai [characters] [Japanese American Education Society]., 1935; (249 pp.) (Box 321)
      - KDA Kisabur [characters]. Beikoku Kash Kyiku-kyoku Tokkyo Sentei Kykaysho: Shni Dai-ni Tokuhon Dokush [characters] [New California State Series School Textbook: The Children's Second Reader]. San Francisco: AOKI Michitsugu., 1906; (372 pp.) (Box 322)
        A translation of an American school textbook.
      - KOND Kikujir [characters]. Fukushú Mondai oyobi Tan [characters] [Review questions and answers, the lectures to Japanese teachers' training classes]. Maui: Maui Kyiku Kai [characters]., 1922; (133 pp.) (Box 322)
      - MIHARA, Tokinobu and Esther Y. Tani. Japanese Reader. San Francisco: Oriental Cultural Institute., 1940; (121 pp.) (Box 322)
      - NAKAYAMA Tenji [characters]. Haha no Kotoba [characters] [The Mother's Tongue]. Los Angeles: Nakayama Tenji Shuppansha., 1924; (277 pp.) (Box 321)
        A supplementary textbook.
      - Nihongo Gakuen Hensan Iin-kai [characters] [Textbook Compilation Committee, Japanese Language Schools]. Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [Japanese Language Reader]. San Francisco: Aoki Taiseid., 1928, 1931, 1939; (5 volumes) (Box 321)
        These textbooks were approved by the California State Board of Education in August 1923.
        vol.1, Revised edition, 53pp., 1931
        vol.2, Revised edition, 51pp., 1939
        vol.4, Revised edition, 88pp., 1928
        vol.11, Revised edition, 102pp., 1939
        vol.13, Revised edition, 4th printing, 106pp. 1931
      - Beikoku Kash Kyiku-kyoku Kentei Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [The Japanese Language Reader approved by the California State Board of Education]. San Francisco: Aoki Taiseid., 1924; (7 books) (Box 322)
        Volumes 1-5, 11, and 13.
      - SUGIMACHI Yaemitsu [characters], ed. Nihongo Tokuhon [characters] [Japanese Language reader], no.10. Los Angeles: Rafu Dai-ichi Gakuen and Pasadena Gakuen., (Mimeographed, 67 pp.) (Box 321)
    - Textbooks Compiled by the Ch Nihon Kyiku Kai [characters], Tule Lake Relocation Center, Newell, California, 1944-1945; 0.5 linear ft.
      - Tokuhon: Kyshi-y [characters] [Reader: Teachers' guide]. Book 5, 7, 10., n.d.; (3 mimeographed books: 96pp.; 142 pp; 150 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Kagai Yomimono [characters] [Supplementary reader]., n.d.; (1 mimeographed book, 96 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Kanbun [characters] [Kanbun]. Book 2, revised edition., n.d.; (1 mimeographed book, 72 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Kmin [characters] [Civic reader]. Book 1-2., (2 mimeographed books: 152pp.; 166 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Pen Shji Kyhon [characters] [Textbook for penmanship], Book 1-2., n.d.; (2 books, mimeographed, 30pp., 63 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Rekishi [characters] [Japanese history]. Book 1-2., n.d.; (2 books, mimeographed, 158pp. and 165 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Senjinkun [characters] [Field Service Code]., n.d.; (1 book, mimeographed, 31 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Shshin [characters] [Shshin]., n.d.; (1 book, mimeographed, 129 pp.) (Box 323)
      - Shshin: Kyshi-y [characters] [Shshin: Teachers' guide]. Book 4., n.d.; (Mimeographed, 130pp., 1 book) (Box 323)
    - Textbooks Compiled by the Monbush [characters] [Ministry of Education of Japan], 0.5 linear ft.
      - Jinj Shgaku Chirisho [characters] [Elementary school geography textbook]. Book 2. Tokyo: Monbush., 1919; (1 book) (Box 324)
      - Jinj Shgaku Kokugo Tokuhon [characters] [Elementary school Japanese Language reader]. Books 7, and 10-12. Tokyo: Monbush., 1929-1934; (4 books) (Box 324)
      - Jinj Shgaku Nihon Rekishi: Kyshi-y [characters] [Elementary school Japanese history textbook: Teachers' guide]. Volume 2. Tokyo: Monbush., 1915; (1 book) (Box 324)
      - Jinj Shgaku Rikasho: Dai-roku Gakunen Kyshi-y [characters] [Elementary school science textbook, 6th grade: Teachers' guide]. Tokyo: Monbush., 1919; (1 book) (Box 324)
      - Jinj Shgaku Shshin-sho [characters] [Elementary school Shshin Textbook]. Tokyo: Monbush. Book 6, 1933; and Volumes 3-4., 1936-1940; (5 books) (Box 324)
      - Kt Shgaku Tokuhon [characters] [Higher elementary school Japanese language reader]. Book 4. Tokyo: Monbush., 1935; (1 book) (Box 324)
      - Shgaku Kokugo Tokuhon: Jinjka-y [characters] [Japanese language reader: Elementary school]. Books 1-5 and 7-12. Tokyo: Monbush., 1932-1938; (11 books) (Box 324)
      - Yomikata [characters] [Japanese language reader]. Book 1. Tokyo: Monbush., 1941; (1 book) (Box 324)
      - Yomikata: Kyshi-y [characters] [Japanese language reader: Teachers' guide]. Book 1. Tokyo: Monbush., 1941; (1 book) (Box 324)
    - Textbooks Compiled and Published in Japan, 1.0 linear ft.
      - FUJIMURA Tsukuru [characters]. Chgaku Shin Kokubun [characters] [Middle school new Japanese language reader]. Book 1. Tokyo: Shibund., 1931; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - FUJIMURA Tsukuru. Teikoku Shin Kokubun [characters] [New Japanese language reader for Imperial Japan]. Books 4-8. Osaka: Miyake Sz Shoten., 1932; (4 books) (Box 325)
      - HAGA Yaichi [characters]. Joshi Shin Kokubun [characters] [New Japanese language reader for girls]. Volume 3. Tokyo: Fuzanb., 1932; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - Hbunkan Henshjo [characters]. Saishin Teikoku Rekishi [characters] [Up-to-date history of Japanese Empire]. Tokyo and Osaka: Hbunkan., 1910; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - HOSHINA Kichi [characters]. Taish Kokugo Tokuhon [characters] [Japanese language reader for the Taish Era]. Revised edition. Tokyo: Ikuei Shoin., 1918; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - Iwanami Henshbu [characters]. Kokugo [characters] [The Japanese language]. Books 1-3 and 5-7. Tokyo: Iwanami Shoten., 1934; (6 books) (Box 325)
      - KOND Toshisabur [characters]. Kokugo Kanbun Seinen Tokuhon: Zen-pen [characters] [Japanese and Kanbun reader: Volume 1]. Tokyo: Ikuseikai., 1911; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - Kyiku Gakujutsu Kenkykai [characters]. Kt Joshi Kaji Kykasho [characters] [Advanced home economics for girls]. Book 1. Tokyo: Dbunkan., 1910; (1 book) (Box 326)
      - MATSUI Kanji [characters]. Joshi Shin Tokuhon [characters] [New Japanese language reader for girls]. Books 1 and 3. Tokyo: Sanseid., 1915; (2 books) (Box 326)
      - MATSUMOTO Shigekichi [characters]. Shinsei Joshi Kokugo Tokuhon [characters] [New Japanese language reader for girls]. Tokyo: Tokyo Kaiseikan. 2nd edition, Books 1-10, 1928; and 3rd edition, Books 2-3., 1932; (12 books) (Box 326)
      - NAKAMURA Hisashir [characters]. Gaikoku Rekishi Kykasho: Tynobu [characters] [World History: Far East]. Revised edition. Tokyo: Sanseid., 1926; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - NITOBE Inaz [characters]. Cht Dai-Nihon Shshin [characters] [Middle school Shshin Textbook]. Volume 1. Tokyo: Dai-Nihon Tosho Kabushiki Kaisha., 1931; (1 book) (Box 325)
      - OCHIAI Sadabumi [characters]. Shintei Chgaku Kokugo Tokuhon [characters] [Middle school Japanese language reader, revised edition]. Tokyo: Meiji Shoin. Book 1-2, 1909; 1912; (2 books) (Box 325)
      - SAT Ky [characters] and KAN'I Masao [characters], comp. Ktei Kt Joshi Tokuhon [characters] [Advanced Japanese language reader for girls, revised edition]. Volume 6. Tokyo: Meiji Shoin., 1922; (1 book) (Box 326)
      - TANAKA Keiji [characters]. Joshi Chgaku Nihon Rekishi Chiri [characters] [Girls' middle school Japanese history and geography]. Revised edition. Tokyo: Sanseid., 1935; (1 book) (Box 326)
      - UOZUMI Sgor [characters]. Kt Shgaku Kokushi Fuzu [characters] [Maps and charts for Kt Shgaku Japanese history classes]. Kt Shgakk 1st and 2nd years. Tokyo: Yukawa Kbunsha., 1934 (Box 325)
      - YOSHIDA Yahei [characters]. Shintei Joshi Kokubun [characters] [New Japanese language reader for girls]. Revised edition. Tokyo: Kinkd Shoseki Kabushiki Kaisha., 1933; (1 book) (Box 326)
    - Supplementary Textbooks (Box 327)
      Materials include Japanese language various subject supplementary textbooks for students, teachers, and parents.
    - Publications regarding Japanese Language Schools, 2.0 linear ft.
      Books regarding the Japanese language schools in America and the Education of the Second Generation.
      - Anonymous. Makawao Nihongo Gakk Shin Kyshi Koy Mondai ni kanshi Akiya-b no Inken Rretsu Ki o Haigekisu [characters]., 1933; (Mimeographed, 26pp. 1 item) (Box 328)
        [I denounce Mr. Akiya's base, deceitful actions in his handling the hiring of a new instructor for the Makawao Japanese Language School]. Maui, Hawaii.
      - ATSUTO Kuwaichi [characters]. Bokoku Kengaku Hkokusho [characters] [Excursion to Japan: A report]. Tokyo: Atsuto Kuwaichi., 1938; (1 item, 77 pp.) (Box 329)